<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-02T18:11:01+08:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Kukaburra</title><subtitle>Aspiring software engineer and a more-than-amateur trumpet player.</subtitle><author><name>Raymond Ku</name></author><entry><title type="html">Python Selenium Implicit Wait</title><link href="/code/2020/05/25/selenium-implicit-wait.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Python Selenium Implicit Wait" /><published>2020-05-25T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/code/2020/05/25/selenium-implicit-wait</id><content type="html" xml:base="/code/2020/05/25/selenium-implicit-wait.html">&lt;p&gt;I am learning Python’s unittest module in combination with Selenium to write an autotesting framework for a webpage at my internship. During the past few days, I wrote more than a dozen tests. Though it was solid progress, the sluggish runtime has driven me mad. After spending hours writing and rewriting my code to see what kind of god forbidden bug is butchering my runtime, my efforts was to no avail. So, I’ve decided to turn to the Selenium documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And right there, RIGHT THERE, on the page about Waits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An implicit wait tells WebDriver to poll the DOM for a certain amount of time when trying to find any element (or elements) not immediately available. The default setting is 0. Once set, the implicit wait is set for the life of the WebDriver object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok…so two things jumped out to me immediately:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implicit wait, once set, applies whenever you’re trying to find elements not immediately available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once set, implicit wait lives as long as the WebDriver object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading that, I immediately knew where I screwed up. When I first started using Selenium, I set an implicit wait of 30 seconds for some reason unbeknownst to me. And now, as you probably saw quite a while ago, that’s what’s causing most of my unit tests to take more than 30 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… I swear from now on I’m going to read documentations more thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ray</name></author><summary type="html">I am learning Python’s unittest module in combination with Selenium to write an autotesting framework for a webpage at my internship. During the past few days, I wrote more than a dozen tests. Though it was solid progress, the sluggish runtime has driven me mad. After spending hours writing and rewriting my code to see what kind of god forbidden bug is butchering my runtime, my efforts was to no avail. So, I’ve decided to turn to the Selenium documentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World!</title><link href="/misc/2020/05/22/hello-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World!" /><published>2020-05-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/misc/2020/05/22/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="/misc/2020/05/22/hello-world.html">&lt;p&gt;This will officially mark the nth time I’ve written the phrase “Hello World”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow, it never gets boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never really blogged before in my life. But I guess there’s a first time for everything. I created this blog thanks to the inspiration from my brother, who also started blogging a few months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main goal for this blog is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Log my progress as a computer science student in college and hope that it resonates with other fellow students out there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Document important, interesting, and even not so interesting events that transpire in my life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Record down my thoughts and feelings about pretty much anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the name “kukaburra” is not a real word. It is a word play on the Australian native kookaburra bird together with my last name. As an Australian who lives overseas, this is my way of paying homage. The kookaburra bird is known for its ridiculous yet rather comedic calling sound that resembles &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S0ZbykXlg6Q&quot;&gt;human laughter&lt;/a&gt;. And as a person who loves to laugh, I hope this blog will reflect that part of my personality and maybe, just maybe, make the world smile a little more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I don’t really know what to expect from this blog. But I guess we will just wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ray</name></author><summary type="html">This will officially mark the nth time I’ve written the phrase “Hello World”.</summary></entry></feed>